Edward U. Condon Papers 1920-1974 Mss.B.C752
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1920-1974; 128 boxes, 64 linear feet
  - Beck, Donald R. Configuration Interaction in the T1 II Spectrum (Box 10)
  - Beck, Donald R. A Relativistic Calculation for Some Optical Levels (Box 11)
  - Beck, Lawrence T. (Box 11)
  - Beckers, Jacques M. (Box 11)
  - Beeman, David E., Jr. (Box 11)
  - Behar, M. F. (Box 11)
  - Behm, Forrest (Box 11)
  - Behnke, John A. (Box 11)
  - Belknap, William J. (Box 11)
  - Bell Telephone Company of Pennsylvania (Box 11)
  - Bell type generator, 6 folders (Box 11)
  - Beltrani, Alvaro V. (Box 11)
  - Benedict, William (Box 11)
  - Benjamin, W. A., Inc., 28 folders (Box 11-12)
  - Benne, Kenneth (Box 12)
  - Bennett, John C., Jerald Brauer, Marice Eisendrath, John Wesley, and Paul Tillich (Box 12)
  - Bennett, Rawson (Box 12)
  - Bennison, B. E. (Box 12)
  - Benson, P. H. (Box 12)
  - Benton, William (Box 12)
  - Bercaw, Roberto and Ruth (Box 12)
  - Bercaw, Ruth B. (Box 12)
  - Berg, Ellison J. (Box 12)
  - Berg, Sigurd (Box 12)
  - Bergmann, Peter G. (Box 12)
  - Bergmann, Peter G. Radiation and Observables (Box 12)
  - Berkeley [Cal.] Society of Friends (Box 12)
  - Bernick, Richard J. (Box 12)
  - Bersohn, Richard (Box 12)
  - Beta Kappa Chi Scientific Society (Box 12)
  - Beth, Richard A. (Box 12)
  - Bethe, Hans A. (Box 12)
  - Betz, Fred M. (Box 12)
  - Bevan, George H. (Box 12)
  - Bhabha, H. J. (Box 12)
  - Bhatnagar, Shanti S. (Box 12)
  - Bhatnagar-Saha Visit, 1944-1945 (Box 12)
  - Bibliography of works by Condon, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Bibliography of the Franck-Condon Principle (Box 12)
  - Biddle, Francis (Box 12)
  - Biermann, Ludwig (Box 12)
  - Bijur, George (Box 12)
  - Billings, Donald E. Problems of the Solar Corona (Box 12)
  - Biographical Materials, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Biological Abstracts (Box 12)
  - Birge, Raymond T., 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Birge, Raymond T. History of the Physics Dept.,U. of Cal., 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Birmingham, Bascom (Box 12)
  - Black, Hugo. We Dissent (Box 12)
  - Blackett, P. M. S. The Ever Widening Gap (Box 12)
  - Blackwelder, Richard E. (Box 12)
  - Blackwell, H. Richard (Box 12)
  - Blaisdell, Warren (Box 12)
  - Blewett, John P. (Box 12)
  - Blitzer, Leon (Box 12)
  - Blizard, J. B. Long-Range Solar-Flare Prediction (Box 12)
  - Blizard, J. B. Solar Activity and Planetary Positions (Box 12)
  - Bloch, Emanuel H. (Box 12)
  - Bloch, Felix (Box 12)
  - Blomfield, Jane Seymour (Box 12)
  - Bloom, Abe (Box 12)
  - Blyholder, George (Box 12)
  - Boas, Ernst P. (Box 12)
  - Boas, George (Box 12)
  - Boekel, William A. (Box 12)
  - Bohm, David (Box 12)
  - Bohr, Niels Henrik David (Box 12)
  - Bok, Bart J. (Box 12)
    See Coryell, Charles D.
  - Bolef, Dan (Box 12)
  - Bolton, Wilbur W., Jr. (Box 12)
  - Book Advertisements (Box 12)
  - Bookbinder, Isidore J. (Box 12)
  - Bork, Alfred M. Collateral Reading for Physics Courses (Box 12)
  - Born, Max (Box 12)
  - Born, Max. Man and the Atom (Box 12)
  - Bos, Mrs. T. (Box 12)
  - Boulder [Colo.] Rotary Club (Box 12)
  - Boulder [Colo.] Sane Nuclear Committee (Box 12)
  - Bowdoin College (Box 12)
  - Bowen, Presley D. (Box 12)
  - Bowen, Roger W. (Box 12)
  - Bowles, Chester (Box 12)
  - Bradbury, Norris E. (Box 13)
  - Bradley, W. H. (Box 13)
  - Bradley, William L. (Box 13)
  - Brahdy, Mrs. Leopold. (Box 13)
    See: Rees, Mina
  - Brahdy, M. R. (Box 13)
  - Branch, John (Box 13)
  - Braniff International Airways (Box 13)
  - Branscomb, Anne (Box 13)
  - Branscomb, Lewis McAdory, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Branscomb, Mrs. Lewis McAdory (Box 13)
  - Brasefield, Charles J. (Box 13)
  - Brauer, Jerald. (Box 13)
    See: Bennett, John C. et al.
  - Breit, Gregory (Box 13)
  - Brewer, A. Keith (Box 13)
  - Brewer, A. Keith. The Dissociation of Hydrocarbon Molecules upon Ionization as Shown by the Mass Spectrometer. (Box 13)
  - Brickwedde, F. G. (Box 13)
  - Bridgers and Paxton Consulting Engineers. Feasibility Study of Solar Heating...Denver Community College, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Bridgman, P. W. (Box 13)
  - Briggs, C. A. (Box 13)
  - Briggs, Lyman James, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Brillowin, L. (Box 13)
  - Brintnall, A. K. (Box 13)
  - British Society for Social Responsibility in Science (Box 13)
  - British War Relief Society (Box 13)
  - Brittin, Wesley E. (Box 13)
  - Brittin, W. E. Topics in Modern Physics. A Tribute to Edward U. Condon (Box 13)
  - Britton, M. G. A Survey of Fallout, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Brode, Bernice. Tales of Los Alamos. (Box 13)
  - Brode, Robert B. (Box 13)
  - Brode, Wallace R. (Box 13)
  - Bronk, Detlev W. (Box 13)
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory (Box 13)
  - Brosseau, Louis (Box 13)
  - Brotzman, Don (Box 13)
  - Brown, E. B. (Box 13)
  - Brown, Harold (Box 13)
  - Brown, Harrison (Box 13)
  - Brown, Kenneth H. (Box 13)
  - Brown, Sanborn C. (Box 13)
  - Brunauer, Stephen (Box 13)
  - Bryant, Howard C. (Box 13)
  - Bryce, William F. (Box 13)
  - Bryn Mawr College. Chemistry-Physics Combined Course (Box 13)
  - Bucher, George H. (Box 13)
  - Buchta, J. W. (Box 13)
  - Buckman, Lorraine V. (Box 13)
  - Buechner, T. S. (Box 13)
  - Buhl, David, et al. The Discovery of Interstellar Formaldehyde (Box 13)
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 26 folders (Box 13-14)
  - Bulletin of the Institute of Physics and the Physical Society, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Buneman, Oscar (Box 14)
  - Bunge, Carlos F. (Box 14)
  - Bureau of National Affairs, Inc. Case Studies in Personnel Security (Box 14)
  - Burford, M. Gilbert (Box 14)
  - Burhop, E. H. S. Exotic Atoms (Box 14)
  - Burkhard, Donald G. (Box 14)
  - Burkhardt, Frederick (Box 14)
  - Burkouskis, Mrs. Anthony (Box 14)
  - Burton, Harold H. (Box 14)
  - Bush, Vannevar (Box 14)
  - Butterfield, Lyman (Box 14)
  - Butterille, Alex De (Box 14)
  - Cahn, Albert S. (Box 14)
  - Cairns, S. S. (Box 14)
  - Caley, Earle R. (Box 14)
  - California. Dept. of Motor Vehicles (Box 14)
  - California Institute of Technology (Box 14)
  - Cambridge [England] Society for Social Responsibility in Science (Box 14)
  - Cambridge University Press, 18 folders (Box 14)
  - Camera. Editor (Box 14)
  - Camp, Glenn Darwin (Box 14)
  - Campaign for Regent, 1966, 42 folders (Box 14-15)
  - Canada. Dept. of Trade and Commerce (Box 15)
  - Canadian Journal of Physics (Box 15)
  - Cannaliato, Vincent J. (Box 15)
  - Cannon, Emerson (Box 15)
  - Cardiff, Ira D. (Box 15)
  - Cardiff, Ira D. Illusions vs. Science (Box 15)
  - Cardwell, A. B. (Box 15)
  - Carlisle, G. T. (Box 15)
  - Carlson, Anton J. (Box 15)
  - Carlson, David (Box 15)
  - Carlton, Margaret (Box 15)
  - Carmichael, Leonard (Box 15)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Carnes, John R. (Box 15)
  - Carter, John (Box 15)
  - Carter, Paul J. (Box 15)
  - Carver, Thomas R. (Box 15)
  - Cary, John C. (Box 15)
  - Case Institute of Technology (Box 15)
  - Cavano, Frank L., Jr. (Box 15)
  - Caviness, Robert S. (Box 15)
  - Cavity Resonators, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Caws, Peter. The Structure of Discovery (Box 15)
  - Centennial Review of Arts and Sciences (Box 15)
  - Center for Research on Conflict Resolution (Box 15)
  - Center for Teaching About Peace and War (Box 15)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Central Cadillac Company (Box 15)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique (Box 16)
  - Ceramic College Review (Box 16)
  - Ceramic Industry (Box 16)
  - Cermak, J. E. (Box 16)
  - Chamber of Commerce [Boulder, Colo.] (Box 16)
  - Chand, Prakash (Box 16)
  - Chang, C. C. (Box 16)
  - Chang, T. C. (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Mrs. Edward S. (Box 16)
  - Chapman, Sydney (Box 16)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, Publishers (Box 16)
  - Chase, Harold W. (Box 16)
  - Chasson, Robert L. (Box 16)
  - Chemical and Engineering News, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Chemical Engineering (Box 16)
  - Chicago Sun Times (Box 16)
  - Chodkiewicz, Michel (Box 16)
  - Chou, T. T. (Box 16)
  - Christensen, Carl J. (Box 16)
  - Christensen, Scott (Box 16)
  - Christman, Ruth C. (Box 16)
  - Chu, L. J. Electrodynamics of Material Bodies (Box 16)
  - Chubb, L. W., 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Church, J. E. (Box 16)
  - Churchmen's Washington Seminar (Box 16)
  - Citizens' Committee for Constitutional Liberties (Box 16)
  - Citizens' Committee to Preserve American Freedoms (Box 16)
  - Citizens for a Non-Partisan University (Box 16)
  - Citizens for Humphrey-Muskie (Box 16)
  - Citizens' Organization for a Sane World, Inc., 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Citron, Robert R. (Box 16)
  - City Club of Rochester [N. Y.], Inc. (Box 16)
  - City College in New York. Student Council - Fair Play for Cuba (Box 16)
  - Clark, John G. (Box 16)
  - Cleary, John Thomas (Box 16)
  - Clemen, Rudolf A. (Box 16)
  - Clemens, Cyril (Box 16)
  - Cleveland [Ohio] Physics Society (Box 16)
  - Coalition on National Priorities and Military Policy (Box 16)
  - Coart, William (Box 16)
  - Cochrane, Rexmond C. (Box 16)
  - Cohen, Bernard L. (Box 16)
  - Cohen, E. Richard & J. W. M. DuMond. Report to the Commission on Nuclidic Masses and Related Atomic Constants... (Box 16)
  - Cole, Kenneth (Box 16)
  - Cole-Parmer Instrument and Equipment Company (Box 16)
  - Colorado Associated University Press (Box 16)
  - Colorado College - Symposium (Box 16)
  - Colorado Committee for Environmental Information, 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Colorado Daily (Box 16)
  - Colorado. Division of Commerce and Development (Box 16)
  - Colorado Environmental Commission. Report (Box 16)
  - Colorado. Governor's Scientific Advisory Commission (Box 16)
  - Colorado. Governor's Scientific Advisory Council, 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Colorado Heart Association (Box 16)
  - Colorado. House of Representatives (Box 16)
  - Colorado Industrial & Research Campus, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Colorado Project/Common Cause (Box 16)
  - Colorado Public Interest Research Group (Box 17)
  - Colorado School of Mines, Golden, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Colorado Scientific Development Commission (Box 17)
  - Colorado State Univ. Advances in Quantum Electronics Symposium (Box 17)
  - Colorado State Univ., Fort Collins (Box 17)
  - Colorado State Univ. Student Peace Research Conference (Box 17)
  - Colorado-Wyoming Academy of Science (Box 17)
  - Columbia University, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Columbus [Ohio] Technical Council (Box 17)
  - Colvin, Charles H. (Box 17)
  - Commission on College Physics, 22 folders (Box 17)
  - Commission on College Physics. Momentum Books, 24 folders (Box 17-18)
  - Committee Concerned About Science and Society (Box 18)
  - Committee for Informed Opinion on Nuclear Arms (Box 18)
  - Committee for Nuclear Information, 13 folders (Box 18)
  - Committee for Preserving Constitutional Rights (Box 18)
  - Committee on the Undergraduate Program in Mathematics, 7 folders (Box 18)
  - Commoner, Barry (Box 18)
  - Commoner, Barry. A Community Effort to Get the Facts; the St. Louis Citizens' Committee for Nuclear Information. (Box 18)
    See: Committee for Nuclear Information
  - Compton, Arthur H. (Box 18)
  - Compton, Arthur H. Atomic Power in War and Peace (Box 18)
  - Compton, Arthur H. Collected Works, 13 folders (Box 18)
  - Compton, Karl Taylor, 6 folders (Box 19)
  - Computer Courses (Box 19)
  - Concerned Voters of Colorado Springs (Box 19)
  - Condon festschrift, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Condon papers, location of (Box 19)
  - Condon, Caroline Marie (Box 19)
  - Condon, E. U. (Box 19)
    - Academic Freedom is no Academic Matter (Address) (Box 19)
    - Address of the President...34th National Conference of Weights and Measures (Address) (Box 19)
    - Aerophysics Seminar Talk, Second Naval Reserve Research, Univ. of Denver (Address) (Box 19)
    - Arms Race - Peril to Mankind (Address) (Box 19)
    - Astronomers and Behavioral Scientists in Collision (Box 19)
    - Atom Smashing at East Pittsburgh (Article) (Box 19)
    - Atomic Bomb is Obsolete (Box 19)
    - Atomic Bomb - It's Loaded (Article), 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Atomic Bombs and the Future (Article) (Box 19)
    - Atomic Bombs and the "Maginot Line" Mentality (Article) (Box 19)
    - Atomic Energy and Industry (Article) (Box 19)
    - Atomic Energy - Servant of Peace (Address) (Box 19)
    - Atomic Era - Can It Bring Peace and Abundance? (Article) (Box 19)
    - Atomic Spectra (Book review) (Box 19)
    - Atomic Threat to Survival (Address) (Box 19)
    - Attack on Scientific Freedom (Article) (Box 19)
    - Autobiography (Box 19-20)
    - Autobiography, Correspondence in re (Box 20)
    - Background of the Atomic Bomb (Article) (Box 20)
    - Basic Research and Human Goals (Address) (Box 20)
    - Beginnings of Nuclear Physics (incomplete) (Address) (Box 20)
    - Better Dead (Article) (Box 20)
    - Bombs-for-Peace Hypocrisy (Article) (Box 20)
    - Lyman James Briggs (Article) (Box 20)
    - Challenge of Science to Human Values (Address) (Box 20)
    - Challenge to Liberalism in the Atomic Era (Address), 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Chemistry of Upper Atmosphere (Address) (Box 20)
    - Prof[essor] A[rthur] H[olly] Compton (Article) (Box 20)
    - Concerning Disarmament (Address) (Box 20)
    - Concerning Education (Address) (Box 20)
    - Concerning Photo-Fission (Address) (Box 20)
    - Continuing to Grow (Box 20)
    - Creativity and Consensus vs. Conformity (Box 20)
    - Curiosities of Mathematics (Box 20)
      See: Condon, E. U. Autobiography #33
    - Demilitarizing the World in the Seventies (Address) (Box 20)
    - Development of American Physics (Address) (Box 20)
    - Development of High Voltage for the Production of Neutrons and Artificial Radioactivity (address) (Box 20)
    - Duty of Dissent (Address), 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Earth's Magnetic Field (Address) (Box 21)
    - Economic Role of Metrology Capabilities (Address), 3 folders (Box 21)
    - [To the] Editor, The San Francisco Chronicle (Box 21)
    - Education for World Understanding (Address), 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Elaboration of the Physical Sciences (Book), 6 folders (Box 21)
    - Electronics and the Future (Address) (Box 21)
    - Elementary Theory of Nuclear Chain Reactions (Address) (Box 21)
    - Excerpts of Remarks at Dinner Meeting of Methodist Peace Meeting (Address) (Box 21)
    - Experiment Reports in Physics 4A - Electricity, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Federal Research Program in the Civilian Agencies. (Address) (Box 21)
    - Federal Support of Science (Address) (Box 21)
    - Fifty Years of Quantum Theory, II (Address) (Box 21)
    - First Decade of the Condon Case (Box 21)
    - Focussing Space-Charge Limited Electron Beams (Address) (Box 21)
    - Food and the Theory of Probability (Article) (Box 21)
    - For an American Resistance Movement (Address) (Box 21)
    - Four Centuries: 17th, 18th, 19th, 20th (Address) (Box 21)
    - Franck-Condon Principle and Related Topics (Address) (Box 21)
    - Freedom and the Future (Address) (Box 21)
    - Freedom on the Campus (Address) (Box 21)
    - Future of Atomic Research (Address) (Box 21)
    - General Analysis of Receiver Behavior, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Geometrical Representation of Physical Magnitudes (Address) (Box 21)
    - Great Decision (Book review) (Box 21)
    - Great Decision (Book review). Response to ..., 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Greatest Opportunity in Human History (Address) (Box 21)
    - H-Bombs for Peace! (Article), 2 folders (Box 21)
    - H Bombs - the morning after (Address) (Box 21)
    - Half-Century of Quantum Physics (Address) (Box 21)
    - Harmony of Science and Religion in Today's Troubled World (Address, article), 2 folders (Box 21)
    - High-Frequency Alternating Currents (Book review) (Box 21)
    - Hiroshima Plus 25 Years (Address), 2 folders (Box 21)
    - How Old is the Universe? (Address) (Box 21)
    - How Science Can Help Win the War (Address) (Box 21)
    - Human Behavior in Societal Activity (Address) (Box 21)
    - Idea of a World University (Book review) (Box 21)
    - Imbalance in Depth (Address) (Box 21)
    - Impact of Quantum Mechanics (Article) (Box 21)
    - Introduction to Theoretical Physics (Book), 53 folders (Box 22-23)
    - Ionospheric Radio Propagation (Box 23)
    - Is There A Science of Instrumentation? (Article) (Box 23)
    - Let's Stop Kicking Uncle Sam's Help Around (Article) (Box 23)
    - Lop-Sided Dice (Box 23)
    - Magnetic Moment of the Free Electron (Article), 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Magnetic Shims, 6 folders (Box 23)
    - Making New Atoms in the Laboratory (Article, address), 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Memorandum Concerning...Atomic Energy Bill (Box 23)
    - More Particles and Bigger Accelerators (Address) (Box 23)
    - Needed: An American Resistance Movement (Address) (Box 23)
    - Needs of Basic Science (Article) (Box 23)
    - Neutron Irradiation Damage in Quartz and Fused Silica (Address) (Box 23)
    - New Frontiers in Atomic Physics (Address) (Box 23)
    - New Opportunities for Engineering (Address) (Box 23)
    - 1962 Nobel Peace Prize (Address) (Box 23)
    - Non-Conservation of Parity in Weak Interactions (Address) (Box 23)
    - Noon Discussion on Science and Public Policy (Address) (Box 23)
    - Note on the Speed of Atomic Particles for Use in Publicity Stories (Article) (Box 23)
    - Note on the Velocity of Sound (Article) (Box 23)
    - Notes for General Session Talk (Address) (Box 23)
    - Notes for Remarks on Academic Freedom (Address) (Box 23)
    - Notes for SANE Talk in Minneapolis (Address) (Box 23)
    - Notes re Ethics/Limits of Science (Address) (Box 23)
    - Notes re History of Quantum Physics (Box 23)
    - Notes re Role of Science in Society (Address) (Box 23)
    - Notes re Solar Energy (Box 23)
    - Nuclear Engineering (Article) (Box 23)
    - Nuclear Forces (Address) (Box 23)
    - Nuclear Motions Associated With Electron Transitions in Diatomic Molecules (Article) (Box 23)
    - On Space-Charge Limited Currents (Article), 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Opportunities of 1960 (Address) (Box 23)
    - Oscillations of a Suspended Chain, 4 folders (Box 23)
    - Outline of Nov[ember] 30 Talk (Box 23)
    - Outline of Talk on Micro-Wave Generation (Address) (Box 23)
    - Past and the Future of the Reviews of Modern Physics (Article) (Box 23)
    - Peace Program (Address) (Box 23)
    - Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy (Book review) (Box 23)
    - Photo-electric Activity and Chemical Constitution (Box 23)
    - Physical Nature of Optical Rotatory Power (Address) (Box 23)
    - Physical Quantities Related to Interatomic Forces (Address) (Box 23)
    - Physician and the Physicist (Address) (Box 23)
    - Physicist and the War (Article) (Box 24)
    - Physicist's Peace (Article, address), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Physics (Article, address), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Physics and the Engineer (Address), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Physics Gives Us - Nuclear Engineering (Article), 4 folders (Box 24)
    - Physics in Industry (Article) (Box 24)
    - Physics in the Engineering Curriculum (Address) (Box 24)
    - Physics of the Glassy State (Address), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Political Misuse of the Personnel Security Problem (Address), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Present Status of Radio-Active Determination of Ages of Rocks (Address) (Box 24)
    - Progress in Understanding Atomic Structure (Lecture), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Prospects for Science in the Seventies (Address) (Box 24)
    - Public Lectures Given Since Coming to Westinghouse (Box 24)
    - Pulpit Editorial for Bill of Rights Day (Address) (Box 24)
    - Pure Rocky Mountain Spring Water (Address) (Box 24)
    - Quantum Mechanics (Article), 6 folders (Box 24)
    - Radiation Sensitive Glasses (Address) (Box 24)
    - Radiative Transfer of Heat from One Plane Sheet to Another (Box 24)
    - Radiative Transport in Hot Glass (Article) (Box 24)
    - Recent Developments in Science (Address) (Box 24)
    - Recent Progress in Radio Astronomy (Address) (Box 24)
    - Recent Progress on Fundamental Physics of the Glassy State (Address) (Box 24)
    - Recollections. Berkeley, 1943 (Box 24)
    - Recollections. Los Alamos, 1943 (Box 24)
    - Religion and Science (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Atomic Energy (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Atomic Weight (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Einstein as a Man (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Glass (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Glass Research (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Nuclear Physics (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Optical Rotatory Power (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Personnel Security and Loyalty (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Radio Astronomy (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About Security Investigation (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About the Need for Progress Toward Peace (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks About the Political Abuse of the Personnel Security System (Address), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Remarks About the Problems of Loyalty and Security Investigations (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks at Testimonial Dinner, April 1948 (Address) (Box 24)
    - (Remarks Made at Friends Meeting) (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks of E. U. Condon at Banquet of American Physical Society... April 28, 1949 (Address), 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Remarks on the Anniversary [25th] of the Atomic Timekeeper (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks on the Teaching of Physics (Address) (Box 24)
    - Remarks Prepared for Dinner at Hotel Biltmore (Box 24)
      See: Condon, E. U. Remarks at Testimonial Dinner, April 1948
    - Reminiscences of a Life In and Out of Quantum Mechanics (Address) (Box 24)
      See: International Symposium on Atomic, Molecular and Solid-State Theory..., 1973
    - Repairing the Damage (Address) (Box 25)
    - Research and Development for Industrial Diversification. (Address) (Box 25)
    - Research at the National Bureau of Standards (Address) (Box 25)
    - Restoring International Cooperation in Science (Address) (Box 25)
    - Review of E. Lazlo, The Systems View of the World (Book review), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Sampling Plans in Purchase Specifications (Address) (Box 25)
    - Science and Freedom (Address) (Box 25)
    - Science and Our Future (Address) (Box 25)
    - Science and Security (Address), 4 folders (Box 25)
    - Science and Social Responsibility (Address) (Box 25)
    - Science and Standards (Address), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Science and Survival (Address), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Science and the Future (Address) (Box 25)
    - Science and the National Welfare (Address) (Box 25)
    - Science in a World at Peace (Address), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Science: Relevance and Responsibility (Lecture), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Science, Secrecy, Security (Address) (Box 25)
    - Scientific Freedom (Address), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Scientific Life in America (Address), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Scientific Technology and Engineering Education (Address) (Box 25)
    - Scientist and His Conscience (Address) (Box 25)
    - Scientist's Responsibility to Society (Address) (Box 25)
    - Scientists and the Federal Government (Address), 3 folders (Box 25)
    - On: Harlow Shapley (Address) (Box 25)
    - Sixty Years of Quantum Physics (Address) (Box 25)
    - Some Thoughts on Science in the Federal Government (Address), 4 folders (Box 25)
    - Special Glasses for Nuclear Work (Address) (Box 25)
    - Statement Before Joint Committee on Atomic Energy. (Box 25)
      See: U. S. Congress. Joint Committee on Atomic Energy
    - Statement Before Senate Committee on Rules and Administration (Box 25)
      See: U. S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Rules and Administration
    - Statement on Science Policy, 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Statement Prepared by E. U. Condon for the Information of his Friends Concerning Recent Articles by Congressman J. Parnell Thomas (Box 25)
    - Strength of Glass (Address), 2 folders (Box 25)